20달러를 바꿀 잔돈이 없어요?
하루 종일 영업을 하셨잖아요
Why can't you change 20 dollars?
You drive all day!
- 그럼 잔돈 바꾸러 갑시다
- 그럴 수 없어요, 잔돈 주세요
- We go get change.
- No, you have to break this.
- 안녕!
Hi !
Hi . . . Can you break a 20?
20달러짜리 바꿀 수 있으세요?
날 따라 하세요
'잔돈은 그냥 가지세요'
Repeat after me:
"Keep the change."
- 잔돈은 그냥 가지세요
- 고마워요
- Keep the change.
- Thank you.
- 맙소사, 배가 떠나요
- 안돼, 기다려요! 잠깐 기다려요!
- Oh my God, the boat!
- Oh, no! Wait!
부인이 안에 계시...
l suppose your wife is . . .
그녀는 흥미 있는 사람들과 있어요
증권 딜러, 회계사, 좋아할 거예요
She's in her element. Stockbrokers,
accountants. She'll enjoy it.
- 당신은 어떡하고요?
- 사실 난 배가 싫어요, 구출된 거죠
- What about you?
- l hate boats. l'm relieved.
- 철갑 상어의 알이지요?
- 그건 철갑 상어가 아냐
- l think this is sturgeon.
- Definitely not.
- 이건 마치 벨벳 같아요
- 스코틀랜드산 연어죠, 최고예요
- lt's like velvet.
- Scottish salmon. The very best.
샴페인 더 하실래요?
More champagne?
- 캘리포니아 산인데 괜찮아요
- 그래요, 감쪽같이 속겠는데요
- lt's not bad, for a Californian.
- You're not kidding. Fooled me.
- 이게 진짜 사는 거죠
- 이제 겨우 막 시작하셨어요
- This is living.
- And it's just beginning.
- 한 번 더 말해 주세요
- 이제 겨우 막 시작하셨어요
- You can say that again !
- And it's just beginning.
고마워요
Thank you.
모시게 되서 영광입니다
칵테일을 준비 할까요? 샴페인?
lt's a pleasure to have you here.
A cocktail? Some champagne?
샴페인? 샴페인!
Champagne? Champagne.
- 배우는 안 하기로 결정 하셨어요?
- 그냥 식당 종업원 하기로 했어요
- You decided not to be an actress?
- l decided to become a waitress.
난 머리를 땋고 다녔거든요
l had the "tress" part right.
잘 나가는 식당 종업원이었고요
And l was a great waitress.
- 식당 산 거 봤어요
- 봤어요?
l saw you bought the place.
- 얼마 전에 지나가다 멀리서 봤어요
- 왜 들르지 않으셨어요?
- l passed by the other day.
- And you didn't come in?
그냥...
많이 바쁘신 것 같아서요
Well, l . . . l figured you were busy.
제발 한번 오세요
어떻게 했나 보셔야죠
Please, you have to come in
and see what l did.
당신의 이름을 새긴 식탁이 있는데
끼니를 굶는 사람들을 위한 거죠
l have a table with your name on it,
for people who can't afford a meal.
물론이죠
당신이 먼저 했잖아요
Of course.
After what you did.
내가 뭘 했는데요? 약속을 했고
그리고 지킨 것뿐이죠!
What l did? l made a promise
and l kept it, period.
- 다들 그렇게 했을 거예요
- 아무도 그렇게 못해요
- Most people would do the same.
- Nobody would !
농담하지 마세요
동화 이야기를 실천한 거예요
Are you kidding?
What you did was like a fairy tale.
그래서 행복하게 잘 살았데요?
동화에서 나오는 것처럼?
And everyone gets to
live happily ever after?
- 희망에 찬 광경이네요
- 그렇게 생각하세요?
- Well, that's a hopeful sight.
- You think?
제 생각은 좀 달라요
어떤 곳에 묶어 두는 것 같아요
l always wonder . . .
What's in store for them?
저들이 행복하게 살까요?
Are they going to be happy?
만일 여자가 50파운드 살이 쪄도
남자가 여자를 사랑할까요?
lf she puts on 50 pounds,
will he love her anyway?
- 결혼하신지 얼마나 되셨어요?
- 삼 년이요
- How long were you married?
- Three years.
에디란 배우하고요
To an actor named Eddie.
우리가 아이를 가지면 알파치노라고
이름을 짓자던 사람이죠
Who suggested, if we had a child,
that we name him Al Pacino.
- Al Pacino Biasi.
- Come on !
- 농담이겠죠!
- 저도 그렇게 말했다고요
뮤리얼하고 난 고등학교 때 만났죠
그저 그런 요리 시간이었는데
Muriel and l met in high school,
in one of those cooking classes -
남학생들은 모두 요리사 복장을 하고
방화 훈련을 한다고...
- where the boys dress like chefs.
And there might be a fire drill . . .
- 당신이 앞치마하고 밖에 나갔고요?
- 맞았어요, 아직까지 소름 끼쳐요
- And you're outside in your aprons?
- Exactly. Even now, l get chills.
아무튼, 데이트를 시작했고...
Anyhow, we started dating, and . . .
뮤리얼은 나에겐 첫 번째 여자...
Muriel was the first girl l ever . . .
정말이에요?
Really?
- 야, 정말 아름답군요
- 그런 것 같아요
- Oh. Well, that's sweet.
- l guess.
혼인 신고하러 갔는데
거기엔 다른 한 쌍이 있었어요
We went to get the marriage licence,
and there was this other couple . . .
- 정통 유태계, 계약 결혼 같은 건데
- 계약 결혼요?
Orthodox Jews.
lt was an arranged marriage.
서로 보는 것이 허용되지 않았어요
곁눈질조차 할 수 없었죠
They weren't allowed to see each
other. They couldn't get a glimpse.
난 생각했어요, '그들은 상대가
매력적인지 조차 모르는구나' 하고
And l thought, "They don't
even know if they're attracted."
서로 얘기가 통할지 조차
모르고 있었고요
"They don't know if they've
got anything to talk about."
십년이 지난 지금, 줄줄이 애 낳고
잘 살고 있을게 틀림없어요
Now, ten years later, l bet they're
happily married with six kids.
하지만 뮤리얼과 난 할 말이 없어요
왜 그런지 모르겠어요
But Muriel and l have nothing
to say. l don't know what happened.
두 개의 채널 속에 있는 것 같아요
난 CNN이고, 뮤리얼은 홈 쇼핑
We're on two different channels.
l'm CN N , she's "Home Shopping".
춤추고 싶지 않으세요?
How would you feel about dancing?
좋은 생각이에요
Oh, l'd . . . be in favour of it.
밤 근무 할 때는 내가 무슨
탐험가 같다는 생각이 들어요
When l was on night shift,
l felt like an explorer.
왜냐하면 이 도시는 밤의 세계가
밤새도록 계속 되거든요
There's this whole other city
that goes on all night long.
- 내가 끊임없이 얘기하고 있죠?
- 그건 그래요
- Am l talking incessantly?
- Yes.
근데 괜찮아요
나도 말이 많은 편이거든요
But l like it.
l myself am a talker.
누군가 함께 얘기하고 거닐 수
있다는 게 너무 다행이지 않아요?
lt's nice to meet somebody you
can just talk with, and hang with.
있잖아요, 난 요즘 거의
하루 종일 아무 것도 안 해요
Look . . . here's the thing.
l'm free all the time, basically.
만일 낮 동안에 뭔가 하고 싶거나
아니면 동료 같은 게 필요하면...
So if you ever want to do something,
or you want company . . .
- 정말이에요?
- 확실해요
Really?
How about tomorrow?
- 내일 어때요?
- 내일이라고요?
- Too soon?
- No, not at all.
- 너무 빨라요?
- 아니, 전혀요
좋아요, 캐럴 보고 계산대 좀
봐 달라고 그러면 되니까
Okay, great. l'll have
Carol watch the register, -
- and you could pick me up at noon?
열두시쯤 데리러 오면 어때요?
- 그래요
- 좋아요
l'll be there.
고마워요
Goodnight.
- 잘 가요
아주 이상한 일이 생겼어
지갑을 밖에 떨어뜨린 줄 알았어
Weirdest thing happened.
l thought l'd dropped my wallet.
아주 이상한 일이 생겼어
배 멀미를 해서 밖에 나갔거든
Weirdest thing happened.
l came out because l felt seasick.
아주 이상한 일이 생겼어...
Weirdest thing happened . . .
- 좋은 생각이 떠올랐어요
- 여보, 이상한 일이 생겼어
- l have some ideas for you . . .
- Weirdest thing happened.
그 송아지 고기 너무 맛있었죠?
Wasn't the veal fabulous?
응, 그게 너무 이상했어
난 닭고긴 줄 알았거든
That was what was so weird.
l expected chicken.
난 당신 옆에 앉으려고 했는데
그로스 씨가 여기 있어서...
l would have come sit with you,
but Mr. Gross . . .
잭 그로스 입니다
만나서 반갑습니다, 경찰관님
Jack Gross.
Pleased to meet you, Officer.
이 분이 우리의 경제 전략을
도와주시겠데요
He's going to help us develop
an economic strategy.
- 그거 좋은 생각인데
- 얼마나 똑똑한 부인인지 몰라요
- What a great idea.
- She's some girl. Smart.
아름다우시고, 그리고
원하는 게 분명하시구요
Beautiful . . .
And she knows what she wants.
- 봐요!
- 저도 동감입니다
- See?
- l agree.
너무 화끈한 저녁이었어요
고마워요, 그로스 씨!
Thank you very much for a
very stimulating evening, Mr. Gross.
- 조언이 필요하시면 언제든지...
- 전화 꼭 드릴게요
- lf you ever need any advice . . .
- l will be calling.
갈 준비 됐어요?
Ready?
- 내 코트 찾아와야 돼요
- 안녕!
- l got to get my coat.
- Bye-bye.
안녕!
- 아주 잘 타는데요?
- 난 균형 감각이 없어요
- You're doing great!
- l never had great balance.
스키를 한번 타 봤는데
유아용 슬로프에만 있었어요
l tried skiing. They threw me off
the "Peter Rabbit" slope.
- 무릎을 굽혀야죠, 그게 문제예요
- 문제 중 하나죠
- Your knees. That's the problem.
- One of them !
여기에 살짝 내리막이 있어요
신경 좀 쓰셔야 돼요
There's a little bit of a hill here,
so you might want to watch it.
- 속도를 줄여요!
- 안 돼요!
- Slow down !
- l can't.
- 확실히 할 수 있어요!
- 확실히 할 수 없어요!
- Sure you can !
- Sure l can't!
- 챨리, 돌아요!
- 알았어요
Charlie, turn !
- 다치지 않았어요?
- 괜찮아요
- Are you okay?
- Fine.
물에서 나병이 옮을 수 있겠지만
그렇지만 않다면 괜찮아요
l'll catch leprosy from the water,
but otherwise l'm okay.
이제 당신하고 롤러 블레이드하곤
이걸로 끝장이겠군요
So l guess this is it
for you and rollerblading?
l would have to say yes.
그렇다고 대답해야겠는데요
좋아요, 당신 차례예요
뭐 하실래요? 뭐 하고 싶으세요?
Okay, your turn. What next?
What do you want to do?
신사 숙녀 여러분,
전 방금 복권에 당첨됐습니다
Ladies and gentlemen,
l've just won the lottery.
오늘 귀갓길은 저와
이반 비아시 양이 책임지겠습니다
Tonight's ride home is on me
and Miss Yvonne Biasi.
- 무슨 일이에요?
- 저 사람들이 토큰을 낸대요
- What's going on?
- They're treating everybody.
- 좋은 일 하기도 어렵네요
- 내가 다 할게요
- This is going to be hard to top.
- l'll top it.
챨리 랭과 이반 비아시 씨를
환영 합니다
Welcome to Charlie Lang,
Yvonne Biasi, -
- Officer Bo Williams -
보 윌리엄 경찰관과
퀸스, 우드사이드에서 온 모든
어린이들도 환영 하는 바 입니다
- and all the kids
from Woodside, Queens.
양키스는 복권 당첨 경관과
식당 종업원을 환영 합니다
알아요, 알아
잘 하려고 노력하고 있다고요
l know, l know.
l'm trying.
어이, 나도 오늘 너무 즐거웠다고
lt was a great day for me, too.
- 저 사람 도대체 왜 그러는 거야?
- 어디엔가 상당히 열 받았는데요
- What the hell is she doing?
- She's pissed, whatever it is.
- 축하해요, 토큰 맨
- 하느님 맙소사!
- Congratulations, Mr. Token Man.
- Oh God !
복권 로빈 후드
- 내 사랑, 나 집에 왔어
- 안돼요, 나가세요
- Honey, l'm home.
- No, you have to leave.
- 마카다미아 땅콩 그만 먹어요
- 키스 한번 하자
- Stop eating my macadamia nuts!
- Give me a kiss.
- 여기 있을 생각 말아요, 나가요
- 왜? 누가 오기로 돼 있어?
- You can't stay here. Out!
- Why? You expecting company?
잘나 빠진 경찰관님
성스러운 짭새 올 거 아냐?
Not Officer Krupke, the saintly cop?
우린 아무 사이도 아니고
그는 성스럽지도 않아요
There's nothing going on.
And he's not a saint, -
단지 점잖은 한 인간이에요
당신은 도저히 흉내도 못 낼...
- simply a decent human being.
Something you couldn't . . .
만일 땅콩 한 알만 더 먹었다간...
lf you eat one more of those . . .
- 당신 그 여자랑 같이 잤어?
- 아냐, 그냥 같이 밖에서 놀았어
- Are you having an affair?
- No, we just hang out together.
당신이 아랫집 여자가 하는 말을
들었어야 해, 그 여자와 일 말이야
You should have heard that bitch
downstairs talking about it.
중요한 게 뭐야? 우리 둘이야
아니면 동네 여편네 일이야?
What's the real issue here? Us,
or what some idiot neighbour thinks?
이건 마치 냉전 시대 같아
내가 무슨 얘길 하려면 당신은...
lt's been like a cold war.
lf l try to talk about it, you . . .
- 난 단지 당신 행복하게 해 주려고
- 아니, 그게 전부가 아니지
- l just tried to make you happy.
- No, that's not all.
내가 밤 늦게 들어 올 때면
날 둘러안곤 했지
l used to come home,
and you'd hug me.
그리곤 키스를 퍼붓곤
하루 일과를 묻곤 했지
You'd kiss me and ask how my
day was. When did you do that last?
오 년 전이 끝이었어
그건 중요한 게 아냐
lt's not important.
lt's history.
- 중요하지 않다고?
- 단지 우리 지난 날의 일부라고
- 당신은 그 여자랑 나돌아 다니면서...
- 난 그 여자랑 잔 적 없어
- You go around with this girl !
- l'm not having an affair.
This thing between you and the cop
is none of my business.
당신과 그 경관과의 관계?
솔직히 내 알 바 아냐
그러나 한 가지
아주 중요한 게 있지, 바로 이거
But . . . there is one thing
that's very important. This:
괜찮아, 두려워 하지 마
Don't be afraid.
'에디 비아시 플레이어스!'
"The Eddie Biasi Players!"
결국은 돈이군요
물론 돈이시겠지요
You want money.
Of course you want money.
착수금으로 5만 달러만 줘
그러면 우린 끝나, 상상해 봐!
Just fifty grand in seed money.
Then we're off. Picture this . . .
Of course not. Not Mr. Saintly.
You're too good to have an affair.
물론 아니겠지, 성스런 분이 어딜!
바람을 피우시긴 너무 착하니까
이젠 그런데 아주 진절머리가 나!
당신의 착함과 그 점잖음!
l'm just so sick of it!
Your niceness and decency.
당신, 아무것도 아냐
일만 하는 바보야! 항상 블루칼라나 해!
You're nothing. A working-class
stiff. Blue collar all the way.
난 변하지 않을 거야, 뮤리얼
l'm not gonna change, Muriel.
알고 있어
l know.
- 그러니까 이혼해
- 이혼을 하자고?
- So l want a divorce.
- You want a divorce?
As soon as possible.
가능하면 빨리
난 이제 날개를 달았다고, 챨리
난 날고 싶어
l have wings, Charlie.
l want to fly.
여보, 내 사랑?
Honey?
The bottom line is, l'm
sticking around until you kick in.
이것만은 알아 둬
당신이 나올 때까지 여길 안 나갈 거야
당신 여기서 아주 살아요
난 아예 나갈 테니까
You stick around.
l'm out of here.
어딜 가는 거야? 큰 마님
Where are you going, big shot?
The Plaza?
- 문에서 비켜요
- 플라자 호텔?
- 그래요, 물 좋은 플라자 가요
- 정말?
Yeah, the Plaza.
그래요, 내가 돌아왔을 때도
여기 있으면 경찰을 부르겠어요
lf you're here when l get back,
l'll call the cops.
지금 난 당장이라도 경찰을 부를 수 있는
조건이 됐다는 걸 기억해요
And believe me, l am now
in a position to get them to come.
- 어디 가요?
- 호텔에
- Where you going?
- A hotel.
- 부인과 찢어지셨다는 말인가요?
- 우리는 역사의 한 페이지가 됐어
- You mean, you and her . . .
- We're history.
- 놀랄 일이 아니네요
- 아냐? 나한테는 그런데!
- Can't say l'm surprised.
- No? lt's funny, l am.
전에 무슨 일이 있었건
이럴 줄은 몰랐지
No matter what comes before,
you don't expect this.
- 챨리, 어느 호텔에 가요?
- 할리데이 인이나 나인스나...
- What hotel, Charlie?
- The Holiday lnn on Ninth.
할리데이 인?
챨리, 복권에 당첨 됐잖아요
Holiday lnn?
Charlie, you won the lottery.
하룻밤 정도는 플라자 같은데 가 봐요
One night at least,
stay at the Plaza.
그럼 그럴까?
너희들 내 친구 같아, 그거 알아?
Maybe l will.
You're a real pal, you know that?
언제 다시 보자
l'll see you guys.
- 안녕하세요
Good evening.
- 방 하나 주세요
- 네, 그러죠
l'd like to get a room.
이상하게 생각하지 말아요
난 그 식당 종업원이 아녜요
l'm not that waitress,
if that's what you're thinking.
아닌 줄 알았어요
l didn't think so.
- 1인용 침대 아니면 2인용 침대?
- 1인용 침대로 주세요
- Single or double?
- A single.
- 흡연실 아니면 금연실?
- 금연실로 주세요
- Smoking or non-smoking?
- Non-smoking.
선생님, 뭘 도와 드릴까요?
Sir, can l help you?
- 그 남자가 다시 들어왔어요
- 그녀가 날 쫓아 냈어요
- He moved back in.
- She threw me out.
811호는 이쪽입니다, 부인
81 1 is this way, ma'am.
선생님, 절 따라오시면 됩니다
Sir?
lf you'll just follow me . . .
- 그 사람, 바로 그 경찰이었어
- 그 여잔 그 식당 종업원이구
- That was the cop.
- That's the waitress.
목욕탕 돌아 보셨어요?
거기 멋진 나이트 가운이 있어요
Checked your bathroom yet?
There's a robe.
- 진짜예요?
- 맹세해요
- Are you serious?
- Swear to God !
- 어... 잘자요
- 들어 와요, 들어 오세요
- Well . . . goodnight.
- Come in.
제 방이랑 똑같이 생겼군요
색깔만 달라요, 믿을 수 없어요
Unbelievable! Your room is exactly
like mine, just a different colour.
과일 좀 드실래요?
Would you like some fruit?
당신 방에도 과일이 있을 거예요
아마 방마다 다 있을 거예요
You have some in your room.
Every room probably has fruit.
- 진짜 나이트 가운이 있어요?
- 타월 옷감이에요
- There's really a robe?
- Terry cloth.
좋아요...
진짜로 좋은 거예요
Nice . . . really nice.
팔더라구요, 백 달러쯤 할 거에요
백 달러가 맞을 거예요
lt's for sale. You can buy it
for like $1 00. l think it's $1 00.
l'll do it.
살래요
절반씩 나눠서 내요, 같이 입어요
한 달동안 당신이 입고 다음에 제가...
l'll split it with you. We'll share.
You have it one month, then me . . .
- Or every other day, or weekends.
- Or we could get two.
- 아니면 하루 걸러나 주말마다
- 또는 두 벌을 살 수도 있구요
- 왜 이렇게 긴장이 되죠?
- 잘 모르겠어요
- Why am l so nervous?
- l don't know.
- 우린 오랜 시간을 같이 보냈어요
- 아마 그래서 그런가 봐요
- We've spent so much time together.
- Maybe that's why.
플라자에서의 하룻밤
사랑의 복권
자, 나갑시다...
Here we go . . .
저기 있다!
There they are!
- 전망이 기가 막히는군!
- 편하게 있으십시요
- Unbelievable!
- Make yourselves comfortable.
- 난 내노라 하는 몇몇 사무실을...
- 월터, 제발요
- l mean, l've seen some offices . . .
- Walter, please.
이 친구들, 당신 팔 다리를 모두
내 놓으라 하겠는데! 이 의자 좀 봐!
They must charge you an arm
and a leg. Just the chairs . . .
- 물 한잔 하실래요?
- 진짜 가죽이야, 그럴줄 알았지
- A glass of water?
- Real leather. l thought so.
- 뮤리얼은 어디 있소?
- 랭 부인은 금방 나가셨습니다
- Where's Muriel?
- Mrs. Lang just stepped out.
그리고 다시 오십니다
And here she is.
- 결국은 크게 하셨구만
- 크게 뭘 했다구?
- You had them done.
- Had what done?
- 시작하죠
- 뭘 했다는 소리야?
- Can we proceed?
- What did she have done?
- 나중에 얘기해 줄께요
- 잡담은 그만 하도록 하죠
- l'll tell you later.
- Let's cut to the chase.
복권 당첨금은 나눠질 수 없습니다
복권은 랭 부인 것 이었습니다
The lottery money should not be
divided. lt was Mrs. Lang's ticket.
- 복권 당첨금은 나눠질 수 없습니다
- 좋아요
- Completely unacceptable.
- lt's all right.
- 그녀에게 내 것의 반을 주겠어요
- 뭐라구?
She can have my half.
이리 와 봐요!
이리 와 보라니까!
Come here.
멍청이야 뭐야?
왜 싸워 보지도 않고 포기해
Are you nuts?
You're giving up without a fight?
재산의 반을 그녀에게
주겠어요, 됐습니다
She can have my half, period.
- 지금 백만 달러가 왔다 갔다 한다고
- 월터, 그만해요
- You're talking a million dollars!
- Walter, please!
농담 하지 마!
You got to be kidding me!
- 요점을 허용합니다
- 성숙된 자세를 보이시는군요
- We concede the point.
- That's a very mature attitude.
그 일전에 있었던 것도 정리해야죠
현재 구좌에 있는 금액이 모두...
As to their pre-lottery holdings,
we have a bank account totalling . . .
삼천 육백 십 일 달러입니다
이것은 꼭 반으로 나눠야 합니다
. . . $3,61 1 .
l insist we split this 50-50.
Chump change.
큰 거스름돈이군
대충 그렇습니다
가구와 옷가지도 있는데...
That's basically it. There's
furnishings, some good linens . . .
셈이 부정확합니다
자쿠토 씨
Not quite accurate, Mr. Zakuto.
랭 선생이 비아시 양에게
준 돈도 여기 첨부했습니다
We are also attaching the monies
given by Mr. Lang to Miss Biasi.
- 말도 안돼!
- 불똥이 엉뚱한 데로 튀는구먼
That is out of bounds!
랭 선생은 아내의 동의 없이
그녀에게 돈을 줬습니다
Mr. Lang volunteered his wife's
earnings without her consent.
이건 너무해, 뮤리얼! 당신이
지금 뭘 하고 있는지 생각해 봐
That's horrible, Muriel. Please,
think about what you're doing.
당신과 비아시 양이 오랜 관계를
가져 왔다고 믿어 의심치 않습니다
We believe that he and Miss Biasi
had a long-standing relationship -
그리고 의도적으로
부인에게 숨겨 온 것 입니다
- that he deliberately
deceived his wife about.
And we have drafted a letter
to Miss Biasi -
여기 비아시 양에게 보낼
편지 초안이 있습니다
당첨금 전부 돌려줄 것을 요구하며
안될 경우 적절한 제재가 따릅니다
- demanding that she return the
money in full, or face penalties.
- 난 더 이상 믿을 수가 없어!
- 돼지 멱따는 소리 듣기 싫어요
- l can't believe this!
- l can't listen to this screaming.
- 우리의 결혼 생활 매일 이랬어요
- 이러지 않았어!
- Our whole marriage was like this.
- lt was not.
이건 이반을 목표로
하고 있는 거야!
ls this just to get even
with Yvonne?
이런 육체적 학대
이젠 신물이나요, 보셨죠?
l am tired of your physical abuse.
Did you see that?
택시 필요하시면 내 비서한테
말해요, 불러줄 거외다
lf you fellows need a cab,
my secretary will call one.
이런 얘기를
어떻게 이반한테 하지?
How am l going to say this
to Yvonne?
챨리, 당분간 그녀를
만나지 않는 게 좋겠어
You'll have to stop
seeing her for a while.
이반 비아시입니다, 전화를 받을 수
없습니다, 메시지를 남겨 주세요
This is Yvonne Biasi. Please
leave a message after the beep.
이반, 당신 생각을 하고 있다고
말하려고 전화 걸었어요
Yvonne, l just wanted to say
l'm thinking about you.
우리가 옳으니까 재판에 이길 거예요
당신은 잘못한 것 없어요
We'll win this, because it's right.
lt's not your fault.
보 집에 있어요, 555-3840 이에요
재판소에서 보게 되겠네요
l'm at Bo's at 555-3840.
l guess l'll see you in court.
마룻바닥에서 자게 되서 어떻게 해요
l hope you don't mind
sleeping on the floor.
- 냉장고에 맥주 있고
- 트레이시, 담요 고마워
- There's beer in the fridge.
- Thanks for the blanket, Tracey.
잘자요, 게일
미안하게 됐네
Goodnight, Gail.
l'm sorry.
뉴욕 시민의 관심을 끌고 있는
재판이 오늘 열리게 됩니다
"The trial, which has attracted
citywide interest, begins today."
- 이런 일이 벌어지다니 말도 안돼!
- 이반이 이겼으면 좋겠어
- This whole thing is unbelievable!
- My money's on Yvonne.
- 당신 생일의 숫자들이 뭐죠?
- 12, 16, 64 입니다
- What are your birthday's numbers?
- 1 2, 1 6, 64.
12... 16... 64 라!
1 2 . . . 1 6 . . . 64.
그리고 결혼기념일의 숫자는요?
And the numbers for
your anniversary, my dear?
6, 26, 84 입니다
6, 26, 84.
6, 26...
6, 26 . . .
제가 26이라고 들었나요?
26?
Did l hear 26?
사실로 말하자면
27일 결혼하지 않았나요?
As a matter of fact,
weren't you married on the 27th?
- 그렇습니다
- 그럼 남편이 26숫자를 골랐군요?
- Yes.
- So your husband picked 26?
- Objection. What's the point?
- The point is, Counsellor . . .
- 반대요! 요점이 뭡니까?
- 요점이 뭐냐 하면요, 변호사님...
요점은요, 존경하는 판사님...
The point is, Your Honour . . .
l am demonstrating -
이건 랭 선생이 복권의 권리 행사를
할 자격이 있다는 것 입니다
- that Mr. Lang is responsible
for the winning ticket.
계속하세요
Overruled.
랭 부인, 남편이 26이란
숫자를 고른 게 맞지요?
So, Mrs. Lang, your husband
picked the 26th on his own, correct?
- 아니요
- 아니라고요?
- No.
- No?
당신이 거기 있었고요...
당신 남편이 거기 있었습니다
There was you . . .
there was your husband . . .
다른 누가, 그 날 아침
거기에 있었습니까?
Who else was there that morning?
내 돌아가신 아버지가 있었어요
My dead father.
- 뭐라구요?
- 돌아가신 아버지요, 편히 쉬소서
- Excuse me?
- My dead father, God rest his soul.
꿈에 나타나셨는데, 창 밖에 둥둥
뜨셔 가지고 저를 부르셨어요
He came to me in a dream. "Baby",
he said, floating out the window.
아버지 등엔 커다란 천사의 날개가 있었고
하얀 가죽 색깔이었어요
He had these big angel wings,
the perfect colour of white leather.
말씀이, '교회 갈 시간이다'
'빨리 안하면 늦겠다' 그러셨어요
He says, "Baby, it's time to go
to the church. You'll be late."
더 놀란 건, 내가 웨딩드레스를
입고서 거기 서 있었어요
To my shock, l'm standing there
in my wedding gown.
퀸스거리에서 플랫부쉬까지
한 걸음에 갔어요, 불가능 하죠
So l run down Queen's Boulevard,
through Flatbush . . . impossible!
교회에 와 보니까, '성 캐터린
거룩 복권'이라고 써 있었어요
l came to the church:
St. Catherine's of the Holy Lotto.
그때야 난 내가 늦지 않은 걸
알았어요, 하루를 일찍 온 거예요
And then l realised l wasn't late,
l was a whole day early.
난 죽고 싶었어요!
God, l wanted to die!
그 때 아버지가 옆에 계셨어요
Then my father was standing
right next to me.
말씀하시길, '얘야 울지 마라'
And he says,
"Little girl, don't cry."
'내겐 기념일이 항상 26일
이란다'라고 말씀 하셨어요
"Because to me, your anniversary
will always be on the 26th."
뮤리얼의 꿈
돌아가신 아버지가 당첨 번호를 뽑다
M U Rl EL'S DREAM
DEAD FATH ER PlCKED Wl N N ERS
랭 선생!
Mr. Lang.
아내를 위해서 아세톤을
사 준 적이 있습니까?
Have you ever purchased
nail polish remover for your wife?
다들 조용히 하세요!
Quiet, please!
아세톤이요?
Nail polish remover?
한두 번쯤이요
- A couple of times, l guess.
- And you paid for it?
- 당신이 돈을 내셨나요?
- 네
그게 당신 것이라고 생각하셨나요?
Did you therefore consider it yours?
그렇게 생각하지 않았습니다
No, l guess l didn't.
당신이 복권을 비아시 양과 나누자고
부인에게 강요하셨나요?
Did you force your wife
to split the ticket with Miss Biasi?
단지 올바른 일을 하자고
얘기했습니다
l only said
we should do the right thing.
- 그때 권총을 차고 있었나요?
- 물론 아니지요
- Were you wearing a gun?
- Of course not.
- You hit her, didn't you?
- l never, ever . . .
- 아내를 구타하셨지요?
- 그런 일 없습니다
당신은 선서를 하셨습니다
랭 선생!
You are under oath, Mr. Lang !
- 한 번 팔을 잡은 일은 있습니다
- 더 이상 질문 없습니다
- Okay, once l grabbed her arm . . .
- No further questions.
복권 경관 아내를 구타하다
- 당신의 증인 입니다
- 고맙습니다, 변호사님
Your witness, Counsellor.
비아시 양! 당신의 재정 상태를
좀 설명해 주시겠어요?
Miss Biasi. Would you describe
your financial circumstances -
- before Mr. Lang offered you
half his wife's winning ticket?
랭 씨가 아내의 복권 당첨금을
당신에게 나눠주기 전의 상황을...
l was struggling to make ends meet.
먹고 살기 힘들 정도였습니다
마스터 카드에 만이천 달러를
빚지고 있었던 게 사실입니까?
lsn't it a fact you owed $1 2,000
on your MasterCard?
- 그건 내 전 남편이...
- '예, 아니오'로만 대답하세요
- That's because my ex-husband . . .
- Just answer yes or no.
문서상 그렇습니다
그렇지만 제가 쓴 건 아닙니다
Technically, yes.
But l hadn't overspent.
그가 당첨금을 준 바로 그날
개인 파산하지 않으셨나요?
Didn't you go bankrupt the same day
he offered to split the ticket?
그렇습니다, 하지만
그건 단지... 운명이었어요
Yes.
But that was just . . . fate.
- 좋습니다, 운명이라...
- 네, 정말이에요
- Right, fate . . .
- Yes. Really.
그가 당첨금을 줄 때
두 분은 어떤 관계였습니까?
What was your relationship with
Mr. Lang when he made his offer?
- 그 전엔 만난 적이 없었습니다
- 정말입니까?
- l'd never met him before.
- Really?
네, 사실입니다
Yes, really.
오늘날의 두 분의 관계에
대해 설명하십시오
Describe your relationship
with Mr. Lang today.
이 세상 그 무엇보다
그를 사랑합니다
l love him more than
anything in the world.
그래서 그가 아내를 버린 날
그와 플라자 호텔에 갔었군요?
And you went to the Plaza
with him the day he left his wife.
- 반대요! 그게 무슨 관계가 있어요?
- 동기요!
- Objection ! What is the relevancy?
- Motivation.
랭 부인이 그를 내 쫓았고
결혼 생활은 다 파괴되 있었는데
Mrs. Lang had thrown him out,
the marriage was in ruins . . .
이 사람과 미디어가 나를 일확천금
노리는 인간으로 만들려고 해요
They're trying to make me into a
gold-digger . . . him, the media . . .
흥분을 자제하세요
비아시 양
Control yourself, please.
l've worked all my life. Finally
something wonderful happened.
난 평생을 일하며 살아 왔어요
이제야 멋진 일이 일어났고요
전 아주 지적이고 친절하며
동정심이 많은 남자를 만났어요
l met a man who was intelligent,
kind and compassionate.
단지 그 분을 아는 것만으로
내 인생이 변했어요, 돈이 아녜요
Just knowing him has
changed my life. lt's not the money.
그는 사람들이 근본적으로 착하다는 걸
믿고 살 수 있게 해줬어요
He made me believe
people were fundamentally decent.
당신이 우리의 관계를 보기 흉하게
만드는 걸 그냥 볼 수만은 없어요
l won't let some lawyer
make our relationship look ugly.
Are you divorced?
- 이혼 하셨나요?
- 아니요
결혼은 이 남자하고 하고
사랑은 다른 사람과 하는군요
You're married to one man,
and in love with another.
- l couldn't afford to get divorced.
- Well, that's convenient!
- 난 이혼을 할 돈이 없었어요
- 그거 아주 편리하게 써 먹네요
연속극 같은 재판에서
이반 비아시 양은
ln dramatic testimony,
Yvonne Biasi was depicted -
돈에 굶주린 색광으로 묘사됐습니다
최종 판결은 오늘 밤에 있습니다
- as a gold-digging nymphomaniac.
A verdict is expected tonight.
- 최종 판결이 내려졌습니까?
- 그렇습니다, 존경하는 재판관님
- Has the jury reached a verdict?
- We have, Your Honour.
말씀하시지요
What say you?
우리는 원고 측인 뮤리얼 랭 여사의
모든 권리를 인정하는 바입니다
We rule in favour of the plaintiff,
Mrs. Muriel Lang, on all counts.
본 법정은 이 재판의 모든
법조인들에게 감사를 드립니다
The court would like to thank
the jury for its service.
본 법정을 파합니다
Court dismissed.
- About your affair with . . .
- Shut up about her!
- 당신과 그녀의 사생활에 대해서...
- 그녀에 대해서 입 닥쳐!
저 아래 있다!
She's down there.
이반!
Yvonne!
- 랭 여사, 한 말씀 해 주시지요
- 정의로운 재판이었죠
- Mrs. Lang? Your reaction?
- Justice was done.
당신의 남편이 선행을 했다고
생각하지 않나요?
Aren't the good deeds
of your husband . . .
우린 만족합니다, 그게 다예요
아주 행복해요
- We're happy, that's all.
- Very happy.
경관과 식당 종업원 패소
그녀가 어디에 있는지 조차 몰라
l don't even know where she is.
이것 봐, 다시 경찰에 복직하면 돼
경찰 일 좋아하잖아
Look . . . You'll be a cop again.
lt's what you love.
난 괜찮을 거야
l'll be all right.
여보세요?
여기 누구 없어요?
ls anyone here?
가세요
Go away.
- 당신 나와 있는 것 안 좋아요
- 그게 무슨 소리예요?
- You don't want to be with me.
- What are you talking about?
- 난 당신을 사랑해요
- 아직도 현실을 이해 못해요?
- l love you.
- Don't you get it?
- 난 당신의 인생을 파괴시켰어요
- 내 자신의 반을 잃어버린 것 같아
- l've ruined your life.
- l feel like half of me is missing.
당신은 4백만 달러에 당첨 됐어요
그게 얼마나 큰 선물인 줄 알아요?
You won $4 million. Do you know
what an amazing gift that is?
And because of me you have nothing.
근데 나 때문에
당신은 알거지가 됐다고요
당신 때문에 난 당신을 가졌어요
왜 그걸 이해 못해
Because of you, l have you.
Why can't you understand?
만일 당신이 날 원치 않는다면
문 밖으로 나가서 다시는 안 오겠소
lf you don't want me, then
l'll walk out that door forever.
하지만 돈 얘기는 그만해요
But please stop talking about the
money. lt means nothing to me.
나에겐 아무 의미도 없는 거예요
내가 이 문으로 나가길 원해요?
Do you want me to go?
아니요
No.
절대로요
Never.
아니고 말구요
Never, never.
가끔씩 날
이해해 줘야 해요, 이건...
You have to excuse me sometimes,
it's just . . .
아무도 이렇게 날 사랑해준
사람이 없었어요
Nobody ever loved me before.
- 저 사람 먹을 걸 원하는 것 같아요
- 들어오게 해도 괜찮을까?
- l guess he wants some food.
- Shall we invite him in?
안될 게 뭐 있어요
Why not?
뉴욕을 떠나야겠어요
We should leave New York.
우리가 이곳에 잘 안 맞는 거 같아요
l mean, we're like freaks here.
버팔로에 사는 사촌이 한 명 있어요
l've got a cousin
that lives in Buffalo.
나한테 항상
좀 들르라고 얘기했어요
He keeps asking me to visit.
한동안 그 곳에 머물 수 있을 거예요
Maybe we can stay there for a while.
난 버팔로 경찰관이 될 수 있고
l could join the Buffalo force.
난 버팔로 식당 종업원 할게요
l could be a Buffalo waitress.
오늘밤, 뉴욕 포스트에서
십 년째 사진기자를 하는 저는
Tonight, l, Angel Dupree,
photographer for the N. Y. Post, -
극단적인 상황에서도 너그러움을
베푸는 모습을 볼 수 있었습니다
- had the chance to study grace and
generosity in dire circumstances.
가장 힘든 시간에도 듬직한 경찰과
마음씨 고운 비아시양은
ln their darkest hour, the stalwart
officer and good-hearted waitress -
나에게 한 그릇의 따뜻한
수프를 나누어 주었습니다
- shared a bowl of soup with me.
'선한 사마리안'들은 내가 떠날 때
나에게 돈까지 주었습니다
When l left,
the good Samaritan gave me money, -
더 많이 못 줘 안타까워하며...
- wishing it could be more.
- 이것 이반의 레스토랑에 보내죠
- 그거 좋은 생각인데
- "Mail it to Yvonne's Coffee Shop."
- lt's a good idea.
마지막으로 한 번만 가볼래요
l just want to make one stop.
- 내 사랑...
- 난 괜찮아요
- Sweetie . . .
- l'm okay.
- 별로 좋은 생각 같지 않아
- 그냥 한 번만 둘러보고 싶어요
- l knew this was a bad idea.
- l just wanted to see it again.
문이 왜 열려 있지?
Why is the gate open?
글쎄요, 캐럴이
열쇠를 갖고 있긴 한데...
l don't know.
Well, Carol has a key . . .
문이 잘 안 열려
The door's stuck.
- 이게 다 뭐야?
- 누가 잘못 전달한 것 아닐까요
- What is this?
- lt must be a mistake.
- 선한 사마리안 기금
- 복권 애호가
- "The Good Samaritan's Fund".
- "Lotto Lovers".
이반 레스토랑
"Yvonne's Coffee Shop."
- 이거 5달러 짜린데?
- 진짜로요?
- lt's five dollars.
- Oh, come on !
당신과 같은 사람들이 더 많아야죠
스테이튼 아일랜드에서 에텔
"There should be more people
like you. Ethel from Staten lsland."
이건 십 달러 짜리 수표야
Here's a cheque for ten.
이거 모두 우리한테 온 거예요
오, 챨리!
This is all for us.
Oh, Charlie!
챨리와 이반을 위한 기금
당신은 우리 모두의 모범이에요
브롱스에서 베티와 나비
"You are an example to all of us.
Betty and Phil. The Bronx."
우린 당신의 미래를 축원해요
롱 아일랜드에서 갈시아스
"We hope you have a great future.
The Garcias, Long lsland City."
이 모든 우편물을 개봉하는데
사흘이 걸렸습니다
lt took them
three days to open all their mail.
마침내 끝났을 때, 모두 육십만 달러의
팁이 모여져 있었습니다
When they were done, New York
had given them a $600, 000 tip.
챨리는 다시 경찰이 됐고요
Charlie went back to the force.
이반은 레스토랑을 찾았습니다
Yvonne got her coffee shop back.
에디는 택시 기사가 됐고요
Eddie could only get work
driving a cab.
그리고 뮤리얼은...
잭 그로스와 재혼을 했는데...
And Muriel ...
She married Jack Gross, -
그가 그녀의 돈을 몽땅 들고
다른 나라로 날랐습니다
- who took her money
and fled the country.
현재 뮤리얼은 브롱스에 있는
손톱 미용실에서 일하고 있습니다
Muriel lives in the Bronx now
and works in a nail salon.
챨리와 이반과 뮤리얼은
모두 한 도시에서 살고 있습니다
Charlie, Muriel and Yvonne
all lived in a city -
기적이 일어나길 기도하는 그 곳에선
가끔 기적이 일어납니다
- where people prayed for miracles.
And sometimes they happened.
경찰과 식당 종업원의 결혼